Kyle Larsen

ABOUT ME

Front-End Developer

Since 2019

A developer with an eye for detail and a love of learning. A master of self-directed skill building and development. Curiosity, creativity and imagination fuel a desire to understand, learn and interact with new ideas and technologies. I have a history of creating elegant and simple applications that prioritize a clean look and easy to understand functionality. As an active member of the Kalamazoo Software Developer Meetup cohort, I am able to keep up with the industry standard and participate in a forum of experienced peers in the field.

EXPERIENCE

Contracted, Schooley & Sons Tackle

October 2019 – Present | Web Developer

- > Worked with client to create a simple and effective design
- > Developed and deployed an ecommerce website
- > Responsive design ensures the site is usable on all screen sizes
- > JAM-stack hosting and server-side render deliver a fast user experience

Freelance, Ten Sleep Rock Ranch Yoga January 2020 – March 2020 | Web Developer

- > Utilize remote communication tools such as zoom, and
- > UI/UX developed along with the client to fit their needs
- > Web app designed using Adobe XD
- > Developed with Vue.js and Firebase to provide data driven reporting for the studio
- > Test for and fix any bugs, working with the client to ensure needs are met

EDUCATION

Calvin University

2010-2014 | Philosophy

PROJECTS

Project Set

February 2020 | May 2020

- > Developed Brand Identity, UI/UX, and marketing strategy
- > JAM-stack Front-End built with Nuxt.js
- > Serverless architecture, using Google's Firebase
- > Allows climbing gyms to track routsetting programs and provides data to fulfill member needs
- > Chart.js provides realtime data visualization making understanding member needs easier

React Expense Tracker

React | Express

- > Node and Express are used to create an API that writes to a Mongo database
- > React is used to create a clean and easy to use UI
- > Helps the user keep track of incoming and outgoing expenses

Route Finder

React | Mountain Project API

- > Axios makes calls to the Mountain Project API
- > React Context manages the global state of the application
- > Uses geolocation to allow the user to find the climbing routes that are nearest to them

SKILLS

JavaScript

ES6 Vue React Node Nuxt Next.js Other



CONTACT

klarsen.me ≥

Kalamazoo, MI

krlars87@gmail.com

(517)-526-1530